In this term, you'll be working on projects to deepen
في هذا الفصل، ستعملون على مشاريع لتعززوا
your understanding of the data analysis process.
فهمكم لعملية تحليل البيانات.
The first project will have you analyzing data
في المشروع الأول ستقومون بتحليل البيانات
collected from people performing the Stroop task.
التي جُمعت من الأشخاص الذين يؤدون مهمة Stroop.
A test of our ability to separate the visual and semantic content of words.
اختبار لقدرتنا على الفصل بين المحتوي البصري والدلالي للكلمات.
We'll use statistics to explore psychological effects associated with this task.
سنستخدم الإحصاءات لاكتشاف التأثيرات النفسية المرتبطة بهذه المهمة.
Most of the data you'll be working with in an actual job,
أغلب البيانات التي ستعملون معها في وظيفة فعلية،
will contain a bunch of errors and other general mess.
ستحتوي على مجموعة من الأخطاء، وغيرها من الفوضى العامة
In the second project, you'll gather data from a variety of sources,
في المشروع الثاني، ستجمعون البيانات من مجموعة متنوعة من المصادر،
assess its quality untidiness and then clean it.
وتقييم جودتها غير المرتبة ومن ثم مسحها.
We'll document your wrangling efforts in a Jupyter Notebook,
سنوثق جهودكم في المعالجة الشاملة في تطبيق Jupyter notebook،
analyze the cleaned up data and report your results through visualizations.
ونحلل البيانات النظيفة وتوضيح نتائجكم من خلال المرئيات.
The third project, you'll apply
المشروع الثالث، ستطبقون
exploratory data analysis techniques to gain an understanding of a data set.
تقنيات التحليل التوضيحي للبيانات لفهم مجموعة بيانات.
You'll explore how variables are distributed,
ستكتشفون كيفية توزيع المتغيرات،
any relationships between variables and check for outliers and anomalies.
وأي علاقات بين المتغيرات والتحقق من المتطرفة والشاذة.
Finally, for the fourth project,
وأخيرًا، المشروع الرابع،
you'll use Tableau to create visualizations from a data set,
ستستخدمون Tableau في إنشاء مرئيات من مجموعة بيانات،
that tells a story or highlights trends or patterns in the data.
تحكي قصة أو تسلط الضوء على الاتجاهات أو الأنماط في البيانات.
Your work should be a reflection of the theory and practice
يجب أن يكون عملكم انعكاسًا للنظرية والممارسة
of data visualization such as visual encodings,
الخاصة بمرئية البيانات مثل الترميزات البصرية
design principles and effective communication.
ومبادئ التصميم والتواصل الفعال.